## Andrés Felipe Pineda Muñoz



November / 23 / 1992  $+57\ 302\ 324\ 2274$ ing.apinedam@gmail.com Bogotá, Colombia

SUMMARY

Systems engineer with emphasis in engineering project management, with 10 years of experience in Java application, using SQL, Oracle-Mongo databases, JPA, Hibernate, ORM, Web Services, Spring Boot, Design patterns, front-end application, design and build application, web applications, SCRUM, Git, AWS and ci/cd.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Specialization in Project Management in Engineering

Universidad La Salle	2020
System Engineer	
Universidad Central	2017
High School Degree	
Instituto Cemoden	2009

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Globant >

#### Globant:

Dic. 2020 - Now Java Developer

Clients like: BCP (Banco de Crédito del Perú) – CitiBanamex – Expedia – FIS - Development and support REST Microwebservices using Java 8 and Spring Boot -Creation of test scenarios and unit tests with JUnit 5 and Mockito - Development of applications and microservices using Java 8, Java 11 and Kotlin - Development of unit tests on components developed using JUnit, Mockito, Groovy. - Management of team tasks, documentation of tasks and tickets, time control, releases to production and support. - Other technologies like GIT, AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Dynamo, Lambda), Apache Kafka.



#### PSL SAS (Now Perficient):

Oct. 2017 - Nov. 2020

Developer Engineer

- Development and support of Java application (version 7 and 8), using Spring Framework and JBrain Framework (PSL) and SCRUM methodology - Support production issues and QA issues - Development of web services with Spring Boot Rest / Soap Administration and control of relational databases such as Oracle and SQL using Hibernate and JPA. - GIT as version control system.



#### Activos S.A:

May. 2017 - Oct. 2017

Developer Engineer

- Development and support of web service like REST and SOAP. Analysis, requirement, design and implementation of applications with J2EE technology using MVC - Administration and control of relational databases such as Oracle and SQL using Hibernate and JPA..



## Megalinea S.A - TGO LTDA (Banco de Bogotá):

Oct. 2015 - May. 2017

Technical Analyst

- Design, analysis and develop process of new technologies for the migration of web services. Analysis, requirement, design and implementation of applications with J2EE technology using MVC - Development and support of web service like REST and SOAP, in the area of Business Productivity - Administration and control of relational databases such as Oracle and SQL using Hibernate and JPA. - Develop applications using

### multi threading technology.

## $\textbf{CERTIFICATION} \ \text{SCRUM FOUNDATION PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE (SFPC) - Certiprof (2020)}$

**LANGUAGES** 

SpanishEnglish

Native

Intermedia (B1 Level)

**SOFTWARE** 

Java 7 - Java 8 - Java 11 - Spring Boot - API Rest - WebServices - Maven - Git - AWS - JUnit 5 -Mockito - Groovy - Kotlin - Oracle SQL Developer - PostgreSQL - MongoDB - JPA - Hibernate - Kafka -Jenkins - Jira - Bitbucket - Confluence - DataDog - Artifactory